hi everybody on today's video we are
going to make arm and Joy or which is
Bounty ice cream so if you want to see
how I eventually got to this perfect
recipe stick around and I'll show
you anyone that follows this channel for
a while uh I did some coconut ice creams
well a couple years ago and I just
weren't quite right I was looking for a
very specific texture mouth feel and
flavor all together and coconut will
make ice cream relatively easily but
it's just not very good ice cream so to
elevate coconut ice cream up to
something that we expect from you know
proper artisanal ice cream
makers I have come up with this there's
a lot of ingredients into this but trust
me it's worth it so what are we going to
need so the first thing you're going to
need is 900 G of coconut milk with
approximately 177% fat you're going to
need 5 61 G of coconut cream with
approximately 21% fat you're going to
need 225 g of plain sugar you're also
going to need 112 G of whipping cream
with approximately 33% fat you're going
to need 50 g of glucose or corn syrup
this is GL glucose 40 de so we're trying
not to increase the sweetness at all
we're also going to need 56 G of arrol
and monk fruit extract
combination 95 G of of skin milk powder
and finally we're going to use a little
bit of stabilizer so there a lot going
into this with the add-ins we're using
shredded coconut or desiccated coconut
if you're in Europe and dark chocolate
if you don't know an arm and joy is
essentially a bounty bar but with an
Armond on the top also covered in
chocolate that that's it they're
identical pretty much in every other way
but getting that texture right is really
really difficult so what we're going to
do
today is make ice cream perfect coconut
ice cream so we're going to use a cold
process stabilizer cuz I don't really
want to heat this up too high but it's a
big kind of batch this you know scale it
down to what you need I haven't even
calculated what that is I'll put the
overall batch size on the screen right
now but we're going to churn this in a
traditional machine and we're also going
to do some in a ninja creamy just to
seeing what the comparison is at the end
and see if one's better than the other
so we essentially just need to get going
we're going to probably Heat this up a
little bit because I want the fats in
the Coconut to emulsify together so you
ready yeah yeah okay let's go right
first thing kiddo let's put this in the
pan it's heavy so I'll help you ready
pour nice now we need to add this in do
you want to help me with
this yeah so this is what creates the
texture that we're after some coconut
creams and coconut milks are really low
in fat and you need to make sure you use
the fat equivalent that is in this
recipe cuz we need that fat to create a
nice texture ice cream so what we're
going to do is just going to pop this on
the heat and get this just like
emulsifying together into a homogeneous
liquid right so we've got our mixture
warmed up and it's not super hot you
know it's like 40 50° Centigrade
something like that and I have put my
glucose syrup in the microwave because
it's super super sticky uh that also
means it's incredibly hot so what we're
going to do is put that in our warm
mixture like so if you use corn syrup
then you probably don't need to heat it
up cuz it's quite it works much less
sticky than than glucose syrup is
so with that in there we're going to
stir that together now we're left with
one liquid and three dry ingredient
got some on my finger so what do we need
to do that is our orthol can you put
that in the pan
please nice thank you and as the liquid
is still warm this is going to help with
the dissolving of our solids this is our
sugar can you put that in a pan please
nice good stuff and now we're going to
put in our whipping
cream it's actually quite an important
you can put it in it's actually quite an
important ingredient in this because
texturally coconut ice cream is very
different to others and when you own a
commercial
outlet coconut ice cream is always like
powdered no one ever makes it because it
doesn't come out the same that inclusion
of dairy is quite important to get the
final result where we need finally we're
going to put in our skim milk powder so
just pop all of that in and with our
powder sitting on the top what I'm going
to do is pop in 2 G of our stabilizer
cold process stabilizer go our gum I I
don't want to heat this up to super high
temperatures you want to give that a
stir for
me it's stirring you are stirring and
you don't stir steady you don't want to
go in over the edge I think we're all
done so one final stage is we got to pop
this is that going to fit in there do
you think let's see let's see you hold
on to
that I'm going to pour this in
only
just only just goes in
there right we are going to pop this in
the refrigerator for a couple of hours
just to bring that residual temperature
back down we just want to get this down
nice and cold so that when we Churn it
it CHS fast that's the point of bringing
these down anyway should we put this in
the fridge yeah yeah and we will come
back when it's ready so our ice cream
base is Cher down spin in the fridge for
all right 4 hours haven't got around to
it what we're going to
do is we're just going to gently stir
this
up
F yeah good the bubbles are done bubbles
are gone so now I am going to help you
pour this into here we're not going to
put it all in all
right ready
I'm not going to fit all in here well
there
[Music]
wh there we go can you press this button
for me with your thumb nice and hard
there we
go and while that's doing that after a
we going to put T and the exess first
we're going to put some in a ninja
creamy tub okay I'll do this you hold
the
tub we're putting it in a ninja creamy
tub like this without any of the add-ins
because we're going to do the add-ins
after so that is now going to go in the
freezer and we will come back during the
dishing up phase so say see you soon see
you
soon so while the ice cream is churning
we take our coconut oil this is actually
deodorized or you know um non-flavored
coconut oil but as this is coconut ice
cream doesn't make any difference put a
little bit of that into your 80% dark
chocolate and melt it gently in a
microwave until it's really nice and
smooth and then we're going to start
adding in our
desiccated coconut or coconut pieces and
get the coconut out of the kids's hair
and all over her face it's basically
everywhere and we're going to keep
loading up there's a lot of coconut
going in this space and that's because
we are after that specific texture right
at the end of the churn we are going to
start loading in our chocolate pieces
it's kind of like a stratch tell and
we're going to load that in nice test
yes it's delicious and we are desperate
to eat some more but hey it is what it
is so after the dish up smells good
Scoops nicely again it's a little bit
harder scoop than I normally go for but
it's loadable solids on go are Armond at
the end of the day this is alond Joy
coat it with our melted chocolate with
that tiny little bit of coconut oil that
is going to freeze nicely as a crackle
top right Al and joy ice cream number
one this is the traditionally churned
one like I said before this texture is
basically everything in this ice cream
you can't just make coconut ice cream
and put an almond on top covered it with
chocolate cover it with chocolate that
doesn't make it an Almond Joy ice cream
having that texture the right amount of
coconut within the base the right flavor
for the base the right consistency of
the ice cream it's key
so we've got to try this I'm
excited
nice m
so
good having all that coconut in
there perfect perfect
consistency perfect
texture those shards of chocolate
throughout just change up a little bit
chocolate crackle top quick note on on
that the more coconut oil you add to
chocolate the slower it will freeze on
your ice cream if you just use chocolate
with nothing else it will freeze really
really quick so don't go too crazy with
the coconut oil you can use any kind of
neutral oil as well olive oil is really
good in I just want to eat this in um
chocolate crackle
top ninja creamy version let's see what
we can do right f is
first let's get
it let's get it spun
I swear that gets longer every
time
right there's our coconut base let's get
a
spoon and we want to get the coconut in
there what does it taste like on
own oh
nice so nice deep well we want to get a
good amount of coconut in here I'm going
to use my hands because I'm the one
eating
this you can use a spoon or a shovel
Spade or a bucket whatever you
want right starting there actually I'm
going to close that over the top I don't
really
want that coconut just to disappear at
the top there we go yeah close that top
back
up it's good ice
[Music]
cream
mixing all
right let's see how we get on with this
one let's get that in there let's get
this one dished up
[Music]
and the ninja let me put the ice cream
back in the freezer the ninja creamy
version obviously this one it doesn't
have the chocolate shards throughout
it's it's too much to have big chocolate
shards in a ninja creamy the blade just
decimates chocolate you absolutely can
but they're not nice big shards I mean
in a traditional chaining machine you
can get shards you know an inch kind of
long but in an inch creamy that tiny
tiny tining it will still taste
excellent so I don't stress about
it nice hard
chocolate let's dig
in can't fold that at all it's slightly
different the coconut isn't as soft
because it hasn't had time to absorb
moisture out of the uh out of the dairy
out the uh so the coconut just a little
bit H harder you know I don't think it's
a bad thing it's just different
chocolate on top beautiful crack man
it's crack
two delicious Almond Joy ice creams one
done in the traditional machine one done
in the Ninja creamy both amazing
results it gives you the same aftertaste
the same after texture as an alond
Joy just to reiterate in Europe you have
the Bounty which is
identical to an Armond Joy but an Armond
Joy has the Armond on top which is also
covered in chocolate they both Armond
joy and Bounty do a milk chocolate and a
dark chocolate version I've chosen to
use dark chocolate here because that's
my favorite by all means substitute that
out for a milk chocolate whatever is
your favorite Armond Joy go with that
chocolate version super
good anyway it only took me what two and
and a half years maybe even more to get
the perfect coconut for me anyway ice
cream thanks very much for watching
don't forget to like And subscribe and
for those that are
interested I have a big box
here of candy that I am going to do
remakes of and maybe even ice cream
versions of as well in the near future
tell me what your favorite candy bar is
obviously this is North American candy
if you're in Europe tell me what your
favorite candy bar is there I can get
candy from Europe as well when Family
come over to visit so let's do some
unique kind of things I wonder if we can
do something ice creamy like this man
that would go hard in ice cream though
don't you freeze these over here
sometimes for the summer but that's
delicious
anyway enough chat thanks much for
watching don't forget to like And
subscribe and I will see you next week